Finding Aid for the James E. Moser Scripts LSC.2219
UCLA Library Special Collections
James E. Moser scripts
1952-1963
UCLA Library Special Collections
Moser, James E.
LSC.2219
7.5 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library, Performing Arts Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7397301
Biographical Note
There is limited biographical information about James E. Moser. Moser was a writer for the radio and television productions of Dragnet. He was also the creator and writer for one of television's first medical anthology shows, Medic and was the creator and producer of the medical drama Ben Casey.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of radio and television scripts related to the career of writer James E. Moser. The bulk of the collection consists of scripts related to the radio and television show Dragnet. Also included are scripts for the television shows Medic and Ben Casey. Additionally, there are a small amount of production stills for the television shows Dragnet and Medic.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series: Series 1. Radio Projects; Series 2. Television Projects.
Related Collections
Jack Webb Papers (Collection 49). UCLA Library Special Collections.
Stanley Meyer Papers (Collection 201). UCLA Library Special Collections.
Television writers -- Archives.; Radio writers -- Archives.; Moser, James E.
- Radio Projects, 1950s
  Scope and Content
  The series consists of one bound volume of scripts for the radio series Dragnet.
  - 22 Rifle for Christmas, 1949 Dec 22 (Box 1)
    General note
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 3.
  - 22 Rifle for Christmas, 1950 Dec 21 (Box 3)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 7.
  - 22 Rifle for Christmas, 1951 Dec 20 (Box 5)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 11.
  - Big .38 (The), 1950 Oct 5 (Box 2)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 6.
  - Big 4th (The), 1952 May 29 (Box 5)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 12.
  - Big 17 (The), 1951 Sept 6 (Box 4)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 9.
  - Big Actor (The), 1950 Aug 10 (Box 2)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 5.
  - Big Almost No Show (The), 1951 Jan 31 (Box 5)
  - Big Affair (The), 1951 Nov 29 (Box 4)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 10.
  - Big Canary (The), 1951 Dec 6 (Box 4)
  - Big Car (The), 1950 Nov 30 (Box 2)
  - Big Cast (The), 1951 Feb 8 (Box 3)
  - Big Couple (The), 1951 Feb 22 (Box 3)
  - Big Crime (The), 1951 Feb 13 (Box 3)
  - Big Badge (The), 1950 May 4 (Box 1)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 4.
  - Big Ben (The), 1951 Mar 15 (Box 3)
    In bound volume Dragnet James E Moser, Vol 8.
  - Big Betty (The), 1950 Nov 23 (Box 2)
  - Big Bindle (The), 1951 May 31 (Box 3)
  - Big Blast (The), 1951 May 17 (Box 3)
  - Big Bomb (The), 1950 July 13 (Box 2)
  - Big Book (The), 1950 Apr 6 (Box 1)
  - Big Border (The), 1952 Mar 20 (Box 5)
  - Big Boys (The), 1950 Mar 16 (Box 1)
  - Big Break (The), 1950 Dec 14 (Box 3)
  - Big Building (The), 1951 June 14 (Box 4)
  - Big Bunco (The), 1952 Apr 17 (Box 5)
  - Big Bungalow (The), 1951 Nov 12 (Box 4)
  - Big Casing (The), 1951 May 10 (Box 3)
  - Big Chance (The), 1950 Aug 24 (Box 2)
  - Big Check (The), 1950 Aug 31 (Box 2)
  - Big Children (The), 1951 Feb 1 (Box 3)
  - Big Church (The), 1950 Oct 26 (Box 2)
  - Big Cliff (The), 1951 June 28 (Box 4)
  - Big Cop (The), 1951 Aug 2 (Box 4)
  - Big Court (The), 1952 Jan 24 (Box 5)
  - Big Crazy (The), 1951 Aug 30 (Box 4)
  - Big Dance (The), 1951 Jan 18 (Box 3)
  - Big Dare (The), 1950 Aug 3 (Box 2)
  - Big Death (The), 1950 Sept 28 (Box 2)
  - Big Drill (The), 1951 May 3 (Box 3)
  - Big Elevator (The), 1952 Apr 24 (Box 5)
  - Big Evans (The), 1952 Mar 6 (Box 5)
  - Big Fake (The), 1950 June 1 (Box 1)
  - Big Family (The), 1950 Dec 28 (Box 3)
  - Big Fire (The), 1952 Mar 13 (Box 5)
  - Big Frame (The), 1950 July 6 (Box 2)
  - Big Friend (The), 1951 Apr 5 (Box 3)
  - Big Gamble (The), 1952 May 8 (Box 5)
  - Big Gangster (The) (part I), 1950 Mar 23 (Box 1)
  - Big Gangster (The) (part II), 1950 Mar 30 (Box 1)
  - Big Gent (The) (part I), 1950 July 20 (Box 2)
  - Big Gent (The) (part II), 1950 July 27 (Box 2)
  - Big Girl (The), 1950 Feb 9 (Box 1)
  - Big Grab (The), no dates (Box 2)
  - Big Grandma (The), 1950 Oct 19 (Box 2)
  - Big Grifter (The), 1950 Feb 23 (Box 1)
  - Big Hands (The), 1951 Nov 22 (Box 4)
  - Big Hit-Run Killer (The), 1951 Nov 8 (Box 4)
  - Big Holdup (The), 1951 Jan 4 (Box 3)
  - Big Honeymoon (The), 1952 Feb 7 (Box 5)
  - Big Imposter (The), 1951 June 7 (Box 3)
  - Big In-Laws (The), 1951 Aug 23 (Box 4)
  - Big Job (The), 1950 Apr 27 (Box 1)
  - Big Jump (The), 1951 Jan 11 (Box 3)
  - Big Juvenile Division (The), 1952 Jan 17 (Box 5)
  - Big Key (The), 1950 May 25 (Box 1)
  - Big Kill (The), 1950 Mar 2 (Box 1)
  - Big Knife (The), 1950 May 11 (Box 1)
  - Big Late Script (The), 1951 July 26 (Box 4)
  - Big Lease (The), 1951 Nov 1 (Box 4)
  - Big Lover (The), 1951 Mar 27 (Box 3)
  - Big Love (The), 1951 July 5 (Box 4)
  - Big Mail (The), 1952 May 15 (Box 5)
  - Big Mailman (The), 1951 May 24 (Box 3)
  - Big Make (The), 1950 Sept 14 (Box 2)
  - Big Man (The) (part I), 1950 Jan 12 (Box 1)
  - Big Man (The) (part II), 1950 Jan 19 (Box 1)
  - Big Market (The), 1951 Oct 25 (Box 4)
  - Big Mink (The), no dates (Box 2)
  - Big Meet (The), 1950 Nov 2 (Box 2)
  - Big Mother (The), 1950 Nov 9 (Box 2)
  - Big New Years (The), 1951 Mar 8 (Box 3)
  - Big Overtime (The), 1951 Dec 13 (Box 5)
  - Big Pair (The), 1950 Sept 21 (Box 2)
  - Big Parrot (The), 1950 Nov 16 (Box 2)
  - Big Partner (The), 1951 Mar 1 (Box 3)
  - Big Phone Call (The), 1952 Feb 14 (Box 5)
  - Big Picture (The), 1950 Dec 7 (Box 2)
  - Big Plant (The), 1952 Feb 28 (Box 5)
  - Big Poison (The), 1950 Sept 7 (Box 2)
  - Big Pug (The), 1950 May 18 (Box 1)
  - Big Purse (The), 1950 June 8 (Box 2)
  - Big Producer (The), 1952 Feb 21 (Box 5)
  - Big Quack (The), 1950 Oct 12 (Box 2)
  - Big Red (The) (part I), 1952 Jan 3 (Box 5)
  - Big Red (The) (part II), 1952 Jan 10 (Box 5)
  - Big Rose (The), 1952 Mar 27 (Box 5)
  - Big Run (The), 1951 June 21 (Box 4)
  - Big Safe (The), 1952 May 1 (Box 5)
  - Big Saint (The), 1951 Apr 26 (Box 3)
  - Big Screen (The), 1951 June 28 (Box 4)
  - Big Set Up (The), 1951 July 12 (Box 4)
  - Big September (The), 1951 Sept 27 (Box 4)
  - Big Shakedown (The), 1952 May 22 (Box 5)
  - Big Shop Lift (The), 1951 Oct 11 (Box 4)
  - Big Show (The), 1952 Apr 10 (Box 5)
  - Big Smart Guy (The), no dates (Box 1)
  - Big Sophomore (The), 1951 July 19 (Box 4)
  - Big Sorrow (The), 1951 Dec 27 (Box 5)
  - Big Sour (The), 1951 Sept 21 (Box 4)
  - Big Speech (The), 1951 Apr 19 (Box 3)
  - Big Story Man (The), 1951 Oct 18 (Box 4)
  - Big Street Car (The), 1952 April 3 (Box 5)
  - Big Thank You (The), 1950 Mar 9 (Box 1)
  - Big Threat (The), 1951 Apr 12 (Box 3)
  - Big Tomato (The), 1951 Jan 23 (Box 3)
  - Big Trail (The), 1950 Apr 20 (Box 1)
  - Big Trunk (The), 1951 Mar 22 (Box 3)
  - Big Watch (The), 1950 Apr 13 (Box 1)
  - Big Waiter (The), 1951 Sept 13 (Box 4)
  - Big Wanted Ad (The), 1951 Oct 4 (Box 4)
  - Big Whiff (The), 1952 Jun 5 (Box 5)
  - Big Winchester (The), 1951 Aug 16 (Box 4)
  - Big Youngster (The), 1950 Aug 17 (Box 2)
  - Garbage Chute Murder (The), 1949 Dec 15 (Box 1)
  - George Quan... The Jade Thumb Rings, 1949 Dec 8 (Box 1)
  - MaxTyler - Escaped Convict, 1950 Jan 5 (Box 1)
  - Mr. Lucky, 1950 Jan 20 (Box 1)
  - Roseland Roof Murder (The), 1949 Dec 29 (Box 1)
  - Spring Street Gang..... Juveniles, 1949 Dec 1 (Box 1)
- Television Projects, 1950s-1960s
  The bulk of the series contains final and revised scripts and a moderate number of production stills for the television series Dragnet. Additionally, there are scripts for the television series Ben Casey, and scripts and a small number of production stills for the television series Medic. The series is arranged alphabetically by television production title; each television production is arranged further alphabetically by episode title. Dragnet and Medic scripts were originally filed in three ring binders. Binders were removed for preservation purposes.
  - Dragnet, 1957-1958
    - Big .38 (The), 1958 Apr 9 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      From loose bound binder labeled, 4151 thru 4171. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - Big Bed (The), 1957 Oct 17 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      From loose bound binder labeled, 4111 thru 4129. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - Big Border (The), 1958 Jan 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Big Bray (The), 1958 Apr 15 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Big Couple (The), 1957 Dec 16 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      From loose bound binder labeled, 4130 thru 4149. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - Big Doll (The), 1957 Nov 30 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Big Donation (The), 1958 Mar 4 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Big Evans (The), 1957 Oct 3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Big Gent (The), 1957 Sept 30 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Big Grifter (The), 1957 Nov 7 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Big Holder (The), 1958 Feb 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Big Honeymoon (The), 1957 Oct 9 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Big Howard (The), 1957 July 31 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Big Irony (The), 1957 Nov 18 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Big Jade (The), 1957 Sept 26 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Big Knot (The), 1957 Sept 23 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Big Love (The), 1957 Sept 13 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Big Mail (The), 1957 Dec 10 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Big Maria (The), 1958 Feb 11 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Big Picture (The), 1958 Jan 21 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Big Red (The), 1958 Apr 24 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Big Roll (The), 1958 Mar 7 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Big Ruthie (The), 1957 Oct 21 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Big Signet (The), 1958 Feb 21 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Big Smart Girl (The), 1958 Feb 14 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Big Sour (The), 1957 Dec 5 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Big Sweet Annie (The), 1957 Nov 29 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Big Tease (The), 1957 Sept 12 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Big War (The), 1957 Oct 8 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Medic, 1950s
    - All The Lonely Night, 1955 Jul 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      From second loose bound binder. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - And There Was Darkness...And There Was Light (Part I), 1955 Aug 8 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - And There Was Darkness...And There Was Light (Part II), 1955 Aug 10 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Black Friday, 1955 Jun (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Candle Of Hope (The), 1955 Aug 24 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Day 10, 1954 Jul 16 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      From first loose bound binder. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - Death Rides Wagon, 1954 Aug (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Glass of Fear (A), undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Glass of Fear (A), undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Annotated. From second loose bound binder. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - I Climb The Stairs, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Just Like Your Father!, 1955 Oct 27 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Laughter And The Weeping (The), 1955 Oct-Nov (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Laugher Is A Boy, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - My Very Good Friend Albert, ca. 1954 Jul 2 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Pray Judgment, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Room, A Boy, and Mister Bodine (A), 1955 Jul (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Time For Sleep (A), 1955 Oct 8 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Duplicate copy see box 4 folder 1. Annotated Ernest Fegte. From second loose bound binder. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - Time For Sleep (A), 1955 Oct 8 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Duplicate copy see box 3 folder 16. Annotated Bill Sickner. From second loose bound binder. Removed from binder for preservation purposes.
    - Walk With Lions, 1955 Jun-Jul (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - When Comes Autumn, 1954 Jul-Aug (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - When I Was Young, 1955 Jul (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - When Mama Says 'Jump!', 1955 Aug 19 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - White Is The Color, ca. 1954 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - World So High (The), 1955 Jun 29 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Ben Casey, 1960s
    - All the Clocks are Ticking, 1962 Feb 16 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - And Even Death Shall Die, 1962 Sept 6 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Arise and Shine, 1962 Mar 6 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Behold a Pale Horse, 1962 Jan 10 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Behold! They Walk an Ancient Road, 1962 July 10 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Between Summer and Winter, the Glorious Season, 1962 Sept 28 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Big Trouble with Charlie (The), 1961 Dec 4 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Blackout, 1962 May 25 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - But Linda Only Smiles, 1961 Aug 9 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Cardinal Act of Mercy (A) (part II), 1962 Oct 19 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Cardinal Act of Mercy (A) (part I), 1962 Oct 18 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Cave Full of Pretty Things (A), 1962 Jun 25 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Coffee Break, 1961 Nov 7 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Dark Night for Billy Harris, 1961 Oct 12 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Father Was An Interne, 1963 Feb 6 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Few Brief Lines for Dave (A), 1961 Sept 6 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - For I Will Plait Thy Hair With God, 1963 Jan 24 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Fly Away Home, 1962 Jan 16 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Girl on the 19th Floor, 1962 Jan 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Go Not Gently Into the Night, 1962 June 15 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Hang No Hats On Dreams, 1963 Mar 19 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Harvest of Hate, 1962 Apr 5 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - He Thought He Saw an Albatross, 1962 Nov 16 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Hundred More Pipers (A), 1962 Nov 19 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - I Hear America Singing, 1962 Oct 4 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - I Remember A Lemon Tree, 1961 Aug 21 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - I'll Be All Right in the Morning, 1962 July 17 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - In the Quiet of the Night, 1961 Nov 17 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - In the Name of Love, A Small Corruption, 1962 Sept 4 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Insolent Heart (The), 1961 July 18 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - It is Getting Dark... And We are Lost, 1963 Mar 25 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - La Vie, La Vie Interieur, 1963 Feb 21 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Lullaby for Billy Dignan, 1963 Mar 8 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Memory of Candy Stripes (A), 1961 Oct 26 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Money Man (The), 1961 Aug 15 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - My Enemy Is A Bright Green Sparrow, 1963 Feb 28 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Monument to an Aged Hunter, 1962 Feb 7 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Narrow Margin, 1961 July 10 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Of All Save Pain Bereft, 1962 July 9 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Other Side of the Hill (The), 1961 Oct 20 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Pack Up All My Care And Woe, 1962 Oct 16 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Piece of Cake (A), 1962 Feb 27 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Preferably, the Less-Used Arm..., 1962 Mar 21 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Rage Against the Dying Light, 1963 Feb 12 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Rigadoon For Three Pianos, 1962 Dec 21 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Saturday, Surgery and Stanley Schultz, 1962 Aug 2 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - So Oft it Chances in Particular Men, 1962 Apr 15 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Short Biographical Sketch of James Tuttle Peabody (A), 1962 Nov 28 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Sound of Laughter (The), 1961 July 5 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Suffer the Little Children, 1962 Nov 28 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Sweet Kiss of Madness (The), 1961 Sept 27 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - To a Grand and Natural Finale, 1962 Jan 31 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Use Neon For My Epitaph, 1962 Nov 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Victory Wears a Cruel Smile, 1961 Dec 19 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Walton Method (The), 1961 Dec 12 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Will Everyone Who Believes in Terry Dunne Please Applaud, 1963 Jan 18 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - When You See an Evil Man, 1962 Apr 24 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - White Ones are Dolphins (The), 1963 Jan 7 (Box 12, Folder 10)